Here's how you might approach the problem of formulating the complete trading strategy.
下面介绍下如何制定完整的交易策略
Our goal is to construct a stock portfolio of long and short positions,
我们的目标是创建一个包含多头和空头的投资组合
and the selection process for stocks to go into the portfolio is
选择股票的依据是
based on the stock's returns performance relative to other stocks.
股票相对于其他股票的收益业绩
For this example, we shall assume
对于本示例
we are periodically re-evaluating and re-balancing stock holdings every month-end.
假设我们每个月底定期重新评估和平衡股票持有情况
Let's use the S&amp;P stocks universe.
我们使用标准普尔作为备选股票池
The top 500 stocks trading in the US tracked by the S&amp;P 500 index.
即标准普尔指数跟踪的美国前 500 只股票
A stock universe, is a general term in finance that refers to
股票池是一个金融术语
a group of stocks that share certain common features,
表示一组具有共同特征
belong to the same market or simply a set of stocks that
并属于同一市场的股票
are used in verifying or simulating trading strategies.
或者是一组用于验证或模拟交易策略的股票
First, we fetch the daily closing prices of each toxins mid-2013.
首先 我们获取在 2013 年入选的每支股票的收盘价
Please note that it is important that we use
请注意 分析时一定要使用
adjusted closing prices for analysis purposes.
调整后的收盘价
Also note that the composition of stock universes changes over time.
还要注意 股票池会逐渐变化
For example, around 10 to 40 companies leave or enter the S&amp;P 500 every year.
例如 每年都有 10 到 40 家公司被选入或落选标准普尔 500 指数
When you test your strategy,
在测试策略时
it is important that your dataset for 2013 for example,
2013 年的数据集应该包含
contained the companies that were part of the universe in 2013.
在 2013 年属于这一股票池的公司
In fact, your dataset for any point in time,
实际上 任何时间点的数据集
should contain the companies that were in the universe at that time.
都应该包含当时在此股票池中的公司
If you use the current composition for example,
如果你使用当前所含的公司
the current S&amp;P 500 index in 2017,
例如在 2017 年的标准普尔指数公司
then you will effectively be testing your strategy
那么你在测试策略时
on the subset of stocks that survive to 2017.
使用的股票是存活到 2017 年的部分股票
These stocks probably performed better than the ones that left the universe.
这些股票很有可能比落选的股票表现更好
So the performance of your strategy will look better than it should.
所以策略的测试效果看起来比实际的要好
This is a subtle error that analysts often make,
分析师经常容易犯这个错
and is known as survivorship bias.
称之为幸存者偏差
Now, since we are only interested in month-end prices,
因为我们只关心月底的价格
we can re-sample the daily closing prices into monthly prices,
所以可以将每日收盘价重采样为每月价格
then we can form a log returns time-series from the monthly prices.
然后对每月价格进行对数收益率时间序列运算
For each month-end observation period,
对于每个月底观察期限
we rank the stocks by their month-end returns from the highest to the lowest.
我们按照从高到低的月底收益率对股票排序
Select the top performing end stocks into
将业绩靠前的股票选做多头投资组合
our long portfolio and the bottom performing end stocks into our short portfolio.
并将表现靠后的股票当做空头投资组合
You could also choose a fraction of stock say,
你也可以选择一部分股票
the top and bottom 10 percent.
例如前 10% 和后 10%
To simplify this example,
为了简化这个示例
we'll assume every stock gets an equal dollar amount of investment.
假设每支股票的投资金额一样
This makes it easier to compute the portfolios monthly returns
这样便于计算投资组合的每月收益
performance as the simple arithmetic average of the stock returns.
直接等于股票收益的算术平均值
Lastly, the combined portfolios monthly returns is
最后 汇总的投资组合按月收益等于
the difference between the long portfolio's return and that of the short portfolio.
多头投资组合的收益减去空头投资组合的收益
Now, continue doing this for each month and
继续对每个月底执行这一流程
period and you have a momentum based trading strategy.
这就是基于动量的交易策略